<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2024//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_240101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">39600184</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2024</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>27</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">2005-6443</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>45</Volume><Issue>6</Issue><PubDate><Year>2024</Year><Month>Nov</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Korean journal of family medicine</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Korean J Fam Med</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Long COVID: A Comprehensive Overview of the Signs and Symptoms across Multiple Organ Systems.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>305</StartPage><EndPage>316</EndPage><MedlinePgn>305-316</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.4082/kjfm.24.0085</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Long coronavirus disease (COVID), also known as the post-acute sequelae of coronavirus disease 2019 (COVID-19) (PASC), is a significant concern since the end of the COVID-19 pandemic, as it still manifests in individuals with persistent symptoms and complications beyond the acute phase of infection. Defining this disease is challenging, as it manifests as a spectrum of symptoms varying in severity among individuals who have previously tested positive for COVID-19. Long COVID is more prevalent in hospitalized COVID-19 patients and presents in various ways, ranging from pulmonary to extrapulmonary symptoms. This literature review examines the current body of research on long COVID with a focus on its effects on the cardiovascular, hematological, respiratory, renal, and neurological systems with systematically analyzed, peer-reviewed articles retrieved from the PubMed database. There have been several proposed pathophysiological mechanisms by which severe acute respiratory syndrome coronavirus 2 affects the aforementioned organ systems; however, research on the definite mechanisms is lacking, especially when considering the management of long COVID in the perioperative setting. The impact of post-COVID sequelae necessitates individualized management strategies tailored to each symptomatic profile, particularly in patients with comorbidities. The COVID-19 pandemic affected millions of people and had a profound impact on those who developed PASC, lowering their quality of life and increasing potential surgical risks. However, there is still uncertainty regarding the specific risk factors for long COVID and who is most susceptible to it. Further research is required to fill these gaps and explore potential avenues for preventing PASC.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Merhavy</LastName><ForeName>Zachary Isaac</ForeName><Initials>ZI</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Ross University School of Medicine, Bridgetown, Barbados.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Junor</LastName><ForeName>Tiana</ForeName><Initials>T</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>University of Medicine and Health Sciences, Basseterre, St. Kitts &amp; Nevis.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Gonzalez</LastName><ForeName>Aranice</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>University of Medicine and Health Sciences, Basseterre, St. Kitts &amp; Nevis.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>De Filippis</LastName><ForeName>Samantha Michelle</ForeName><Initials>SM</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>University of Medicine and Health Sciences, Basseterre, St. Kitts &amp; Nevis.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Oveisitork</LastName><ForeName>Sarah</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>St. George's University, True Blue, Grenada.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Rivera</LastName><ForeName>Eliu</ForeName><Initials>E</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>University of Medicine and Health Sciences, Basseterre, St. Kitts &amp; Nevis.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ndukwu</LastName><ForeName>Ifeanyi</ForeName><Initials>I</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>University of Medicine and Health Sciences, Basseterre, St. Kitts &amp; Nevis.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Bhatara</LastName><ForeName>Kanika</ForeName><Initials>K</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Family Medicine, Wayne State University School of Medicine, Rochester, MI, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2024</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>20</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Korea (South)</Country><MedlineTA>Korean J Fam Med</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101502902</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2005-6443</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CommentsCorrectionsList><CommentsCorrections RefType="CommentIn"><RefSource>Korean J Fam Med. 2024 Nov;45(6):303-304. doi: 10.4082/kjfm.45.6E</RefSource><PMID Version="1">39600183</PMID></CommentsCorrections></CommentsCorrectionsList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">COVID</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Cardiology</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Epidemiology</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Hematology</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Long COVID</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Nephrology</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Pulmonology</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>
<b>CONFLICT OF INTEREST</b>
. No potential conflict of interest relevant to this article was reported.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2024</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>22</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2024</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>21</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2024</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>27</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>20</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2024</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>27</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>19</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2024</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>27</Day><Hour>2</Hour><Minute>47</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2024</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>1</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39600184</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.4082/kjfm.24.0085</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">kjfm.24.0085</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11605154</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Yang C, Zhao H, Espin E, Tebbutt SJ. Association of SARS-CoV-2 infection and persistence with long COVID. Lancet Respir Med. 2023;11:504&#x2013;6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10171832</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37178694</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gonzalez-Garcia P, Fiorillo Moreno O, Zarate Penata E, Calderon-Villalba A, Pacheco Lugo L, Acosta Hoyos A, et al. From cell to symptoms: the role of SARS-CoV-2 cytopathic effects in the pathogenesis of COVID-19 and long COVID. Int J Mol Sci. 2023;24:8290.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10179575</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37175995</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kenny G, Townsend L, Savinelli S, Mallon PW. Long COVID: clinical characteristics, proposed pathogenesis and potential therapeutic targets. Front Mol Biosci. 2023;10:1157651.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10171433</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37179568</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pavli A, Theodoridou M, Maltezou HC. Post-COVID syndrome: incidence, clinical spectrum, and challenges for primary healthcare professionals. Arch Med Res. 2021;52:575&#x2013;81.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8093949</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33962805</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>O&#x2019;Mahoney LL, Routen A, Gillies C, Ekezie W, Welford A, Zhang A, et al. The prevalence and long-term health effects of long COVID among hospitalised and non-hospitalised populations: a systematic review and meta-analysis. EClinicalMedicine. 2022;55:101762.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9714474</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36474804</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Magnavita N, Arnesano G, Di Prinzio RR, Gasbarri M, Meraglia I, Merella M, et al. Post-COVID symptoms in occupational cohorts: effects on health and work ability. Int J Environ Res Public Health. 2023;20:5638.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10178744</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37174158</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Roever L, Cavalcante BR, Improta-Caria AC. Long-term consequences of COVID-19 on mental health and the impact of a physically active lifestyle: a narrative review. Ann Gen Psychiatry. 2023;22:19.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10174610</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37170283</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen TH, Chang CJ, Hung PH. Possible pathogenesis and prevention of long COVID: SARS-CoV-2-induced mitochondrial disorder. Int J Mol Sci. 2023;24:8034.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10179190</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37175745</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xie Y, Xu E, Bowe B, Al-Aly Z. Long-term cardiovascular outcomes of COVID-19. Nat Med. 2022;28:583&#x2013;90.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8938267</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35132265</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Konig BH, van Jaarsveld CH, Bischoff EW, Schers HJ, Lucassen PL, Olde Hartman TC. Prognostic factors for persistent fatigue after COVID-19: a prospective matched cohort study in primary care. Br J Gen Pract. 2023;73:e340&#x2013;7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9926286</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37105729</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yu Z, Ekstrom S, Bellander T, Ljungman P, Pershagen G, Eneroth K, et al. Ambient air pollution exposure linked to long COVID among young adults: a nested survey in a population-based cohort in Sweden. Lancet Reg Health Eur. 2023;28:100608.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9989696</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37131862</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Morello R, Mariani F, Mastrantoni L, De Rose C, Zampino G, Munblit D, et al. Risk factors for post-COVID-19 condition (long COVID) in children: a prospective cohort study. EClinicalMedicine. 2023;59:101961.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10101848</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37073325</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yasmin F, Najeeb H, Naeem U, Moeed A, Atif AR, Asghar MS, et al. Adverse events following COVID-19 mRNA vaccines: a systematic review of cardiovascular complication, thrombosis, and thrombocytopenia. Immun Inflamm Dis. 2023;11:e807.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10022421</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36988252</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mirnia K, Haji Esmaeil Memar E, Kamran N, Yeganedoost S, Nickhah Klashami Z, Mamishi S, et al. Short-term side effects of COVID-19 vaccines among healthcare workers: a multicenter study in Iran. Sci Rep. 2024;14:4086.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10876545</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38374372</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bostanci A, Gazi U, Tosun O, Suer K, Unal Evren E, Evren H, et al. Long-COVID-19 in asymptomatic, non-hospitalized, and hospitalized populations: a cross-sectional study. J Clin Med. 2023;12:2613.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10095523</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37048697</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Arnold DT, Milne A, Samms E, Stadon L, Maskell NA, Hamilton FW. Symptoms after COVID-19 vaccination in patients with persistent symptoms after acute infection: a case series. Ann Intern Med. 2021;174:1334&#x2013;6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8252827</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34029484</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ayoubkhani D, Bermingham C, Pouwels KB, Glickman M, Nafilyan V, Zaccardi F, et al. Trajectory of long COVID symptoms after COVID-19 vaccination: community based cohort study. BMJ. 2022;377:e069676.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9115603</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35584816</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bergmans RS, Chambers-Peeple K, Yu C, Xiao LZ, Wegryn-Jones R, Martin A, et al. &#x2018;I&#x2019;m still here, I&#x2019;m alive and breathing&#x2019;: the experience of Black Americans with long COVID. J Clin Nurs. 2024;33:162&#x2013;77.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10624641</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37140186</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hua MJ, Gonakoti S, Shariff R, Corpuz C, Acosta RA, Chang H, et al. Prevalence and characteristics of long COVID 7-12 months after hospitalization among patients from an urban safety-net hospital: a pilot study. AJPM Focus. 2023;2:100091.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10036151</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37131536</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fukushima H, Imai H, Miyakoshi C, Naito A, Otani K, Matsuishi K. The sustained psychological impact of coronavirus disease 2019 pandemic on hospital workers 2 years after the outbreak: a repeated crosssectional study in Kobe. BMC Psychiatry. 2023;23:313.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10157547</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37143062</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Parhizgar P, Yazdankhah N, Rzepka AM, Chung KY, Ali I, Lai Fat Fur R, et al. Beyond acute COVID-19: a review of long-term cardiovascular outcomes. Can J Cardiol. 2023;39:726&#x2013;40.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9901229</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36754119</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Adjaye-Gbewonyo D, Vahratian A, Perrine CG, Bertolli J.  Atlanta (GA): Centers for Disease Control and Prevention; 2023. Long COVID in adults: United States, 2022 [Internet] [cited 2024 Apr 4]. Available from:  https://www.cdc.gov/nchs/products/databriefs/db480.htm.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37756137</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bhatt VR, Jawade PG, Patel AM, Palange A, Adapa S. Post-COVID multisystem inflammatory syndrome-adult leading to cardiomyopathy and autoimmune thyroiditis: a case report. Cureus. 2023;15:e33754.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9922567</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36793837</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Abbasi J. The COVID heart-one year after SARS-CoV-2 infection, patients have an array of increased cardiovascular risks. JAMA. 2022;327:1113&#x2013;4.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35234824</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Daines L, Zheng B, Pfeffer P, Hurst JR, Sheikh A. A clinical review of long-COVID with a focus on the respiratory system. Curr Opin Pulm Med. 2022;28:174&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7612723</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35131989</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pretorius E, Vlok M, Venter C, Bezuidenhout JA, Laubscher GJ, Steenkamp J, et al. Persistent clotting protein pathology in long COVID/post-acute sequelae of COVID-19 (PASC) is accompanied by increased levels of antiplasmin. Cardiovasc Diabetol. 2021;20:172.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8381139</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34425843</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Seshadri M, Ahamed J, Laurence J. Intervention in COVID-19 linked hypercoaguable states characterized by circuit thrombosis utilizing a direct thrombin inhibitor. Thromb Update. 2020;1:100009.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7476895</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38620488</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cushman M. Epidemiology and risk factors for venous thrombosis. Semin Hematol. 2007;44:62&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2020806</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17433897</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hajra A, Mathai SV, Ball S, Bandyopadhyay D, Veyseh M, Chakraborty S, et al. Management of thrombotic complications in COVID-19: an update. Drugs. 2020;80:1553&#x2013;62.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7429134</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32803670</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Abou-Ismail MY, Diamond A, Kapoor S, Arafah Y, Nayak L. The hypercoagulable state in COVID-19: incidence, pathophysiology, and management. Thromb Res. 2020;194:101&#x2013;15.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7305763</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32788101</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Varga Z, Flammer AJ, Steiger P, Haberecker M, Andermatt R, Zinkernagel AS, et al. Endothelial cell infection and endotheliitis in COVID-19. Lancet. 2020;395:1417&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7172722</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32325026</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Iba T, Levy JH, Connors JM, Warkentin TE, Thachil J, Levi M. The unique characteristics of COVID-19 coagulopathy. Crit Care. 2020;24:360.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7301352</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32552865</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dixit NM, Churchill A, Nsair A, Hsu JJ. Post-acute COVID-19 syndrome and the cardiovascular system: what is known? Am Heart J Plus. 2021;5:100025.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8223036</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34192289</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cares-Marambio K, Montenegro-Jimenez Y, Torres-Castro R, Vera-Uribe R, Torralba Y, Alsina-Restoy X, et al. Prevalence of potential respiratory symptoms in survivors of hospital admission after coronavirus disease 2019 (COVID-19): a systematic review and meta-analysis. Chron Respir Dis. 2021;18:14799731211002240.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7975482</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33729021</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Becker RC. Evaluating chest pain in patients with post COVID conditions permission to think outside of the box. J Thromb Thrombolysis. 2023;55:592&#x2013;603.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10098243</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37052772</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shi S, Qin M, Shen B, Cai Y, Liu T, Yang F, et al. Association of cardiac injury with mortality in hospitalized patients with COVID-19 in Wuhan, China. JAMA Cardiol. 2020;5:802&#x2013;10.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7097841</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32211816</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rohun J, Dorniak K, Faran A, Kochanska A, Zacharek D, Danilowicz-Szymanowicz L. Long COVID-19 myocarditis and various heart failure presentations: a case series. J Cardiovasc Dev Dis. 2022;9:427.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9785067</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36547424</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Knight DS, Kotecha T, Razvi Y, Chacko L, Brown JT, Jeetley PS, et al. COVID-19: myocardial injury in survivors. Circulation. 2020;142:1120&#x2013;2.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7492396</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32673505</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Melchior SE, Schoos MM, Gang U, Jacobsen PK, Wiese L, Melchior TM. Recurring episodes of bundle branch reentry ventricular tachycardia due to aortitis preceded by SARS-CoV-2 infection: a case report. BMC Cardiovasc Disord. 2023;23:46.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9875172</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36698058</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Qamar MA, Afzal SS, Dhillon RA, Sajid MI, Sarfraz Z, Sarfraz A, et al. A global systematic review and meta-analysis on the emerging evidence on risk factors, clinical characteristics, and prognosis of multisystem inflammatory syndrome in adults (MIS-A) Ann Med Surg (Lond) 2023;85:4463&#x2013;75.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10473365</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37663717</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Diekman S, Chung T. Post-acute sequelae of SARS-CoV-2 syndrome presenting as postural orthostatic tachycardia syndrome. Clin Exp Emerg Med. 2023;10:18&#x2013;25.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10090716</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36718484</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yates T, Haffner SM, Schulte PJ, Thomas L, Huffman KM, Bales CW, et al. Association between change in daily ambulatory activity and cardiovascular events in people with impaired glucose tolerance (NAVIGATOR trial): a cohort analysis. Lancet. 2014;383:1059&#x2013;66.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24361242</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stavrou VT, Tourlakopoulos KN, Vavougios GD, Papayianni E, Kiribesi K, Maggoutas S, et al. Eight weeks unsupervised pulmonary rehabilitation in previously hospitalized of SARS-CoV-2 infection. J Pers Med. 2021;11:806.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8399744</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34442450</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tang Y, Jiang J, Shen P, Li M, You H, Liu C, et al. Liuzijue is a promising exercise option for rehabilitating discharged COVID-19 patients. Medicine (Baltimore) 2021;100:e24564.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7886442</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33578552</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Raj SR, Guzman JC, Harvey P, Richer L, Schondorf R, Seifer C, et al. Canadian Cardiovascular Society position statement on postural orthostatic tachycardia syndrome (POTS) and related disorders of chronic orthostatic intolerance. Can J Cardiol. 2020;36:357&#x2013;72.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32145864</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tian S, Xiong Y, Liu H, Niu L, Guo J, Liao M, et al. Pathological study of the 2019 novel coronavirus disease (COVID-19) through postmortem core biopsies. Mod Pathol. 2020;33:1007&#x2013;14.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7156231</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32291399</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Leung TY, Chan AY, Chan EW, Chan VK, Chui CS, Cowling BJ, et al. Short- and potential long-term adverse health outcomes of COVID-19: a rapid review. Emerg Microbes Infect. 2020;9:2190&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7586446</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32940572</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yan Z, Yang M, Lai CL. Long COVID-19 syndrome: a comprehensive review of its effect on various organ systems and recommendation on rehabilitation plans. Biomedicines. 2021;9:966.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8394513</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34440170</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang F, Kream RM, Stefano GB. Long-term respiratory and neurological sequelae of COVID-19. Med Sci Monit. 2020;26:e928996.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7643287</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33177481</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>PHOSP-COVID Collaborative Group Clinical characteristics with inflammation profiling of long COVID and association with 1-year recovery following hospitalisation in the UK: a prospective observational study. Lancet Respir Med. 2022;10:761&#x2013;75.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9034855</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35472304</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chippa V, Aleem A, Anjum F. Postacute coronavirus (COVID-19) syndrome. Treasure Island (FL): StatPearls Publishing; 2024.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34033370</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huang L, Yao Q, Gu X, Wang Q, Ren L, Wang Y, et al. 1-year outcomes in hospital survivors with COVID-19: a longitudinal cohort study. Lancet. 2021;398:747&#x2013;58.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8389999</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34454673</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Song WJ, Hui CK, Hull JH, Birring SS, McGarvey L, Mazzone SB, et al. Confronting COVID-19-associated cough and the post-COVID syndrome: role of viral neurotropism, neuroinflammation, and neuroimmune responses. Lancet Respir Med. 2021;9:533&#x2013;44.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8041436</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33857435</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stavem K, Ghanima W, Olsen MK, Gilboe HM, Einvik G. Persistent symptoms 1.5-6 months after COVID-19 in non-hospitalised subjects: a population-based cohort study. Thorax. 2021;76:405&#x2013;7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7716295</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33273028</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bowe B, Xie Y, Xu E, Al-Aly Z. Kidney outcomes in long COVID. J Am Soc Nephrol. 2021;32:2851&#x2013;62.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8806085</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34470828</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Al-Aly Z, Agarwal A, Alwan N, Luyckx VA. Long COVID: long-term health outcomes and implications for policy and research. Nat Rev Nephrol. 2023;19:1&#x2013;2.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9628426</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36319780</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Copur S, Berkkan M, Basile C, Tuttle K, Kanbay M. Post-acute COVID-19 syndrome and kidney diseases: what do we know? J Nephrol. 2022;35:795&#x2013;805.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8924729</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35294747</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Legrand M, Bell S, Forni L, Joannidis M, Koyner JL, Liu K, et al. Pathophysiology of COVID-19-associated acute kidney injury. Nat Rev Nephrol. 2021;17:751&#x2013;64.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8256398</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34226718</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>G&#x142;owacka M, Lipka S, M&#x142;ynarska E, Franczyk B, Rysz J. Acute kidney injury in COVID-19. Int J Mol Sci. 2021;22:8081.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8347536</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34360866</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Atiquzzaman M, Thompson JR, Shao S, Djurdjev O, Bevilacqua M, Wong MM, et al. Long-term effect of COVID-19 infection on kidney function among COVID-19 patients followed in post-COVID-19 recovery clinics in British Columbia, Canada. Nephrol Dial Transplant. 2023;38:2816&#x2013;25.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37349962</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Martin de Francisco A, Fernandez Fresnedo G. Long COVID-19 renal disease: a present medical need for nephrology. Nefrologia (Engl Ed) 2023;43:1&#x2013;5.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10060193</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37031074</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schiffl H, Lang SM. Long-term interplay between COVID-19 and chronic kidney disease. Int Urol Nephrol. 2023;55:1977&#x2013;84.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9955527</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36828919</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li D, Liao X, Ma Z, Zhang L, Dong J, Zheng G, et al. Clinical status of patients 1 year after hospital discharge following recovery from COVID-19: a prospective cohort study. Ann Intensive Care. 2022;12:64.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9272871</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35816225</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yende S, Parikh CR. Long COVID and kidney disease. Nat Rev Nephrol. 2021;17:792&#x2013;3.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8427150</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34504319</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Monje M, Iwasaki A. The neurobiology of long COVID. Neuron. 2022;110:3484&#x2013;96.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9537254</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36288726</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Reiss AB, Greene C, Dayaramani C, Rauchman SH, Stecker MM, De Leon J, et al. Long COVID, the brain, nerves, and cognitive function. Neurol Int. 2023;15:821&#x2013;41.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10366776</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37489358</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhao S, Toniolo S, Hampshire A, Husain M. Effects of COVID-19 on cognition and brain health. Trends Cogn Sci. 2023;27:1053&#x2013;67.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10789620</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37657964</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Volk P, Rahmani Manesh M, Warren ME, Besko K, Goncalves de Andrade E, Wicki-Stordeur LE, et al. Long-term neurological dysfunction associated with COVID-19: lessons from influenza and inflammatory diseases? J Neurochem. 2024;168:3500&#x2013;11.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38014645</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Asadi-Pooya AA, Akbari A, Emami A, Lotfi M, Rostamihosseinkhani M, Nemati H, et al. Long COVID syndrome-associated brain fog. J Med Virol. 2022;94:979&#x2013;84.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8662118</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34672377</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Granholm AC. Long-term effects of SARS-CoV-2 in the brain: clinical consequences and molecular mechanisms. J Clin Med. 2023;12:3190.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10179128</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37176630</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Oronsky B, Larson C, Hammond TC, Oronsky A, Kesari S, Lybeck M, et al. A review of persistent post-COVID syndrome (PPCS) Clin Rev Allergy Immunol. 2023;64:66&#x2013;74.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7896544</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33609255</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Watanabe A, Iwagami M, Yasuhara J, Takagi H, Kuno T. Protective effect of COVID-19 vaccination against long COVID syndrome: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Vaccine. 2023;41:1783&#x2013;90.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9905096</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36774332</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Malesevic S, Sievi NA, Baumgartner P, Roser K, Sommer G, Schmidt D, et al. Impaired health-related quality of life in long-COVID syndrome after mild to moderate COVID-19. Sci Rep. 2023;13:7717.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10175927</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37173355</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>